<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A letter sent from Maynhem concerning the late defeate giuen the Duke of Brunswicke by Monsieur Tilley Whereunto is added a couranto of other newes from Vienna, Prague, the Palatinate and other places this 20. of Iune. 1622.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1622</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 12 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 5 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A08160</idno>
            <idno type="STC">STC 18507.54</idno>
            <idno type="STC">STC 17256</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC S103375</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99839131</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99839131</idno>
            <idno type="VID">3530</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A08160)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 3530)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1475-1640 ; 1246:14)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A letter sent from Maynhem concerning the late defeate giuen the Duke of Brunswicke by Monsieur Tilley Whereunto is added a couranto of other newes from Vienna, Prague, the Palatinate and other places this 20. of Iune. 1622.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[4], 7, [1] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by Bernard Alsop for Nathaniel Butter,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1622.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>The first leaf is blank.</note>
                  <note>Identified as STC 17256 on UMI microfilm.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the Henry E. Huntington Library and Art Gallery.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Tilly, Jean T'Serclaes, --  Comte de, 1559-1632.</term>
               <term>Thirty Years' War, 1618-1648 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-01</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-01</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-02</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-02</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:3530:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:3530:1"/>
            <p>A LETTER SENT FROM MAYNHEM CONCER<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning the late defeate giuen the Duke of Brunſwicke by Mon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſieur <hi>Tilley.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Whereunto is added a Couranto of other newes from <hi>Vienna, Prague,</hi> the <hi>Palatinate</hi> and other places this 20. of <hi>Iune.</hi> 1622.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON.</hi> Printed by <hi>Bernard Alſop</hi> for <hi>Nathaniel Butter.</hi> 1622.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:3530:2"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:3530:2"/>
            <div type="letter">
               <head>THE COPIE OF A LETTER SENT FROM Mainhem the 20. of <hi>Iune</hi> 1622.</head>
               <p>
                  <seg rend="decorInit">S</seg>IR, ſince my laſt, wee receiued a packet certifying; that about the fifteenth or ſixeteenth of this month that before the Duke of <hi>Brunſwicke</hi> could paſſe the riuer <hi>Maine,</hi> ſtaying a day and a night after hee had built his bridge at the towne of <hi>Hoeſt</hi> two Dutch mile from <hi>Franckfort,</hi> hearing that <hi>Tilley</hi> with his army of 24000 was aduancing towards him, reſolues to ſtay to giue him bartle, ſo looſing his opportunitie of paſſing the bridge with his whole army, at laſt perceiuing the greatneſſe of <hi>Tilleys</hi> army, and by the perſwaſion of his Councell of warre, makes all the haſt hee could to put ouer his army, all his foote being ſafely paſſed be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing about 10000. men, and his horſe about 7000. a great part of them hauing paſt the bridge with all of his treaſure, and ſome Canon; <hi>Tilley</hi> ſo ſpeedily pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſues his rereward of horſe, that he ſlue at leaſt 1000. of his horſe, tooke three Earles, the one of them called Count <hi>Leuiſtone,</hi> taking a great part of his baggage, and three peeces of Canon. And it is reported that a peece of Ordnance being diſcharged by <hi>Tilley,</hi> brake the bridge, which as was thought was the occaſion that
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:3530:3"/>
                  <hi>Brunſwicks</hi> loſt ſo many of his horſe for want of paſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſage, others ſuppoſe it was done by <hi>Brunſwicke</hi> to preuent Monſieur <hi>Tilleys</hi> purſuite, it is thought that <hi>Brunſwicke</hi> the ſame day, or the next morning, came to the King of <hi>Bohemia,</hi> and the Marqueſſe of <hi>Baden:</hi> It is certaine, that <hi>Tilley</hi> cannot get to <hi>Openheme</hi> with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out a long and tedious march, with many difficulties.</p>
               <p>Count de <hi>Lip</hi> is one of the three Earles, priſoners.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="letter">
               <head>
                  <hi>This Letter came from</hi> Bruſſe<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ls, dated the 24. of Iune.</head>
               <head type="sub">
                  <hi>From Vienna the</hi> 24. <hi>of Maie.</hi> 1621.</head>
               <p>Yeſterday is his Imperiall Maieſtie happily arriued with 5000. men at <hi>Odenburgh,</hi> and was receiued with great pompe and ſtate of the <hi>Hungarians;</hi> whether the propoſition ſhall be done to day o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> to morrow, is yet vnknowne.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Thurſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </hi> is come to <hi>Odenburgh</hi> with 600. horſe, but his Ladies ſickeneſſe cauſed his ſpeedy departure.</p>
               <p>The <hi>Hungarians</hi> declare that they wil not haue two Kings, or that the Span-ſhips, or the confederated, and the beſt part of all <hi>Hungary</hi> to be giuen vnto <hi>Beth<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lem Gabor,</hi> and deſire neuertheleſſe to be ſecured a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt the <hi>Turkes,</hi> who make great preparations.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="letter">
               <head>
                  <hi>From Prague this</hi> 26. of <hi>Maie.</hi> 1622.</head>
               <p>The Duke of <hi>Bauaria,</hi> hauing written for great aide vnto the Emperour, his Maieſtie had conſented the <hi>Holſteyniſh Saxiſh</hi> 1000. horſe ſhall ioyne with him: they are muſtered now, the <hi>Holſteyniſh</hi> lie at <hi>Liedtmo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rich,</hi> and the Saxiſh in <hi>Pa<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>dmer</hi> kreits.</p>
               <p>They of <hi>Glats</hi> hauing made a ſally out of the Cittie, haue taken 140. oxen that were driuing towards <hi>Prage</hi>
                  <pb n="3" facs="tcp:3530:3"/>comming from <hi>Pruſsia,</hi> and conducted them to their Cittie.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="letter">
               <head>A coppy of a truſtfull Letter from Vienna the <hi>27.</hi> of May. <hi>1622.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>Fauourable Lord and friend, the warres in the Em<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pire are made in the Empire with enough diſorder, and it ſeemeth that the Duke of <hi>Bauaria</hi> doth but little preuaile with his forces; And <hi>Tilley</hi> impoueriſheth the Country by the contributions: He fauours much the Biſhop of <hi>Wirtsburgh,</hi> but it is to be feared that hee is not able to helpe his Lordſhip much in his preten<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion.</p>
               <p>Concerning the peace or warre of <hi>Hungary,</hi> we ſhal now ſoone know what will be the <hi>Hungarian</hi> dyet, which vpon ſome new conditions offered by the Em<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perour, is now begunne at <hi>Odenburgh,</hi> where the Em<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perour met with <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>00. horſe and foote. The Ambaſſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dours of <hi>Bethlem Gabor;</hi> and the States of <hi>Hungarie</hi> with 12000. And the Lord <hi>Budeani</hi> went thither with 6000. men. There is great longing for the propoſiti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on and iſſue of this diet.</p>
               <p>They maruell at <hi>Conſtantinople</hi> that <hi>Bethlem</hi> is en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tred ſo deepe in this treatie of peace, without giuing any notice afore-hand of it vnto the great <hi>Turke:</hi> but ſeeing <hi>Bethlem</hi> hath not ſent thither any body to giue accompt of his dealing and further enterpriſe, the <hi>Turke</hi> hath likewiſe not yet reſolued what he will doe. In the meane time he hath ſent an army of forty thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſand men, vpon the frontires of <hi>Hungaria,</hi> and appoin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted Generall of the Campe, the Viceroy of <hi>Gracia,</hi> ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uing beene before <hi>Baſhaw</hi> of <hi>Buda.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="letter">
               <pb n="4" facs="tcp:3530:4"/>
               <head>From <hi>Bunten</hi> this 24.</head>
               <p>Thoſe of <hi>Predigaw</hi> haue as yet ſtrongly beſieged <hi>Meyevelt</hi> being 8000. in number both horſe and foote. The beſieged haue ſlaine in two ſeuerall places 1200. of their enemies, and driuing many of them in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to the riuer, did get at their great need aboundance of armour and munition, and looke yet for more ayde of their confederates that are aſſembled at <hi>Baden.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Thoſe of <hi>Zarich</hi> haue ſent vnto them of <hi>Predigaw</hi> before <hi>Ma<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>euelt</hi> 600. men and three peeces of Orde<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nance, beſides diuers Petards: Thoſe of the <hi>Glarer</hi> haue ſent them likewiſe two hundred men, and they looke for more ayde from other places, and haue beſet the paſſe.</p>
               <p>The beſieged of <hi>Ma<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>euelt</hi> write, that if they be not reſcued, within a fort night they muſt ſurrender them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelues, the Canon playing mightily vpon their cittie.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="letter">
               <head>From <hi>Strasburgh</hi> the 2. of <hi>Iune.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>From <hi>Switſerland</hi> wee vnderſtand that the <hi>Griſons</hi> keepe themſelues brauely, hauing lately defeated the ſocours come from <hi>Millaine,</hi> driuing the reſt backe, which cauſed the Gouernour of <hi>Millaine</hi> to reſolue to come into the field himſelfe in the defence of the houſe of <hi>Auſtria,</hi> and to take with him the <hi>Spaniſh</hi> Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>giments, and that of the Collonell <hi>Serbellone,</hi> leauing the gouernment of the Dukedome into the hands of the <hi>Caſtelein,</hi> charging him to raiſe two Regiments more during his abſence, to bee imployed in time of neceſſi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>e, The <hi>Griſons</hi> re-enforce themſelues like<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:3530:4"/>being aſſiſted with 60000. Gilder by the <hi>Swiſſers</hi> as other friends.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="letter">
               <head>From <hi>Franefort</hi> the 9. <hi>Iune.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>The king and the Count of <hi>Mansfield</hi> lyes yet at <hi>Darmſtat</hi> and is not yet knowne when they will depart nor whether. The whole land is declared priſe, but burning and murdering prohibited vpon life, there is great ſtore of Kine and Sheepe to day conueyed in this cittie, the Magiſtrates haue bought many of them, becauſe the people may redeeme them againe for the money layd out, as is done already by many.</p>
               <p>The Count <hi>Lodwic</hi> is yet at <hi>Darmſtat.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Yeſterday is the <hi>Spaniſh Commiſſarie,</hi> S. de <hi>Fort</hi> beſides the Rector of <hi>Hochſt</hi> taken priſoner by this Cittie and carryed away.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="letter">
               <head>From <hi>Franckfort</hi> the 12. of <hi>Iune.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>By my former Letters is aduiſed that the king of <hi>Bohemia</hi> was <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>riued in the Land of the Count <hi>Darm<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtat,</hi> which is mightily ſpoyled by the ſouldiers. The King was yet the 8. day of this moneth in the cittie of <hi>Darmſtat,</hi> but the next day he intended to go towards the Biſhoprick of <hi>Ments.</hi> In the interim had the ſayd Count treated with the King vpon ſome poynts which the King propounded, but the Count not liking the conditions, went on Thurſday laſt with his ſonne pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uately out of the Cittie to ſaue themſelues there, but was taken within a mile of the ſayd Citty by the Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>queſſe of <hi>Durlach</hi> being ſtrong 8000. foote and 1600.
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:3530:5"/>horſe, and conueyed againe to <hi>Darmſtat,</hi> which flight cauſed the army not to depart ſo ſoone.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="letter">
               <head>From <hi>Ments</hi> the 10. of <hi>Iune.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>We vnderſtand here that the Count Lodwicke of <hi>Darmſtat</hi> by command of the King of <hi>Bohemia</hi> is ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ken priſoner, and with a ſtrong conuoy both of horſe and foote conducted to <hi>Mainhem,</hi> &amp; his land is made priſe, excepting onely burning, murdering and like ſhamefull actions.</p>
               <p>The cauſe is as they ſay, that the Count (aforeſayd) a while agoe had written Letters againſt the king of <hi>Bohemia</hi> directing the ſame vnto the Magiſtrate of <hi>Hidelbergh.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>The Count of <hi>Mansfield</hi> hath demanded from the <hi>Iewes</hi> at <hi>Franckfort</hi> a notable ſumme of money, they ſay 150000. Rix Dollers, it is reported that they of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fer 12000.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="letter">
               <head>From <hi>Hanan</hi> the 6. of Iune.</head>
               <p>The Lord of <hi>Anholt</hi> is with his forces lying neere <hi>Frankfort,</hi> but two miles from <hi>Mansfelt,</hi> of both ſides they come within the Citty threatning one another.</p>
               <p>The Marqueſſe of <hi>Durlach</hi> is ariued at <hi>Baſheym,</hi> how ſtrong, is not yet knowne. Monſieur <hi>Tilley</hi> is about <hi>Aſchaſſenbach,</hi> with whom ioyne the forces ſent lately from <hi>Bauaria:</hi> whether <hi>Anholt</hi> ſhall doe the like, is vn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>certaine.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="letter">
               <head>From Collen the <hi>11.</hi> of Iune.</head>
               <p>The Lord of <hi>Anholt</hi> is with the moſt part of his forces at <hi>Aſchoppenburch;</hi> where it is thought that <hi>Til<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ley</hi>
                  <pb n="7" facs="tcp:3530:5"/>ſhall come to meete him.</p>
               <p>The <hi>Spaniſh</hi> forces haue broken the bridge at <hi>Op<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>penheim,</hi> reſoluing to make another at <hi>Steyn.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>The duke <hi>Chriſtian</hi> of <hi>Brunſwike</hi> did lie about <hi>Gota,</hi> taking his way towards <hi>Franken-land.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Yeſterday did Count <hi>Mansfield</hi> ſend a Trumpet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter, to ſommon <hi>Steynheymb</hi> (lying vpon the Riuer of <hi>Meyn</hi>) to ſurrender it, but was anſwered, that they had nothing for him but gun-powder and lead.</p>
               <p>The Elector of <hi>Ments</hi> fearing <hi>Mansfield,</hi> hath com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>maunded the trees about the Citty to be cut downe, and the Ordenance to be planted vpon the walles; be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſides other preparations to defend the Citie.</p>
               <p>Count <hi>Henry</hi> of <hi>Naſſau,</hi> is the firſt of Iune ariued at <hi>Arnhem,</hi> trauelling in all ſpeed to <hi>Embricke;</hi> there are ſent many ſhippes vpwards the <hi>Rheine,</hi> with ſoul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>diers and warlike preparations.</p>
               <p>The 11. of Iune, is finally concluded and granted by the high and mighty Lords the States generall of the vnited Prouinces, the Weſt-<hi>India</hi> company, wher<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in they trafficke for ſalt, and the negociation vpon <hi>Guinea</hi> are comprehended, to the great good liking of all good Patriots. And the ſubſcribing ſhall laſt vntill the laſt of Iuly, being two moneths after the reſoluti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on afore-ſaid, but forreiners ſhall haue three moneths.</p>
               <p>The King of <hi>Denmarke</hi> commaunds two thouſand horſe to be leuied, which his Maieſtie ſhall maintaine at his owne charges in the ſeruice of the vnited Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uinces.</p>
            </div>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
